Privacy is a major component of information security.
Once we know how private the information is,
we know what appropriate controls can be implemented.
A number of standards,
policies and procedures govern privacy in the working environment.
And these vary by geographic region
in the United States, Hipaa,
the health insurance,
portability and accountability Act controls how the
privacy of medical information must be maintained
in the European Union. Eu
the general data protection regulation gives anyone within the borders of the
eu control over what personal information
companies can compile and retain about them
as a security professional.
It's important to be aware of privacy laws and
regulations in all jurisdictions where your company conducts business.
When doing business in other countries,
we must be aware of their privacy standards and regulations and act accordingly.